# **ANSHIKA DIXIT**

# Delhi,India 7533843990 anshikadixit210@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A detail-oriented professional with demonstrated strategy, communications, and marketing skills and experience in marketing and public relations. Successful at coordinating campaigns and being a team player. With approximately two years of experience managing many national and international projects with teams from Edelman and starting new ventures using self-learned marketing techniques.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **SELF-EMPLOYED**

### Marketing Consultant (Freelance)

11/2023 to Current

As an independent marketer, I help new and established businesses, such as Aira, D Square, ASEL, and Synecdoche Media, meet their overall marketing goals.

- I collaborate with the marketing and communications teams by continuously identifying opportunities for new marketing campaigns and by standardising, designing, and implementing PR strategies
- I look at sales at Synecdoche Media
- Craft marketing plans based on extensive research and prospect targeting
- Manage a combination of effective PR campaigns, email marketing, content for websites, blogs, SEO, and special event marketing
- Manage launch of new products and content releases, from planning to implementation
- Supported Aira in developing their overall comms and PR strategy

### **EDELMAN**

New Delhi

### **Associate Account Executive**

10/2022 to 08/2023

At Edelman, I assisted clients like Walmart and their initiatives and commitments in the Indian market, as well as SABIC, one of the largest petrochemical companies. I also overlooked communications for Reach to Teach, a social impact organisation that aims to educate children in the remotest areas with limited financial means My responsibilities

- Worked towards enabling farmers and Micro, small and medium enterprises under the Walmart Foundation and Vriddhi programmes, respectively
- Produced and managed communication plans and organised events in the presence of key official dignities, such as cabinet ministers and senior Walmart global leadership
- Drafted six press releases and pitched creative story ideas to secure Financial Times and Times of India for editorial placements
- Stayed updated on marketing developments through regular research, communicating changes in regards to policies to implement into PR strategies

### **EDELMAN**

Public Relations Intern 07/2022 to 09/2022

I worked with clients from the social impact and development sector during my internship at Edelman, including The/Nudge, which focuses on delivering sustainable livelihoods in India and reducing poverty, and Toilet Board Collaboration TBC, which strives to provide sanitation solutions in Africa and India.

• I collaborated directly with content and account managers to write press releases, obtain proper coverage through a compelling narrative, and bring our clients' concerns into the public eye

### **WEBINDIA MASTER**

### **Digital Marketing Intern**

01/2022 to 03/2022

At Webindia Master, I got the chance to work with the lifestyle brand Casio, fashion labels like Rue fashion and Zoom, as well as brand management for a news broadcasting channel.

### Responsibilities

- Closely analysed data to assess the performance and success of digital marketing campaigns
- Used software like Canva to develop graphics for marketing content. Managed clients' social media accounts like Twitter, Instagram, Facebook, and Youtube.
- Also, creating engaging content and responding efficiently to comments, messages, and reviews
- Used detailed SEO expertise to improve online platform reach and engagement
- Used hub spot, WordPress, and LinkedIn website builders to manage website activities, including uploading blogs and updating web copy

### **VALUE 360 COMMUNICATIONS**

### **Public Relations Intern**

07/2021 to 09/2021

Responsibilities

- I tracked media coverage on world events and reported research to my clients from Edtech and Fintech sectors Contributed to media relations strategy across online, broadcast, and print
- Created engaging content for social media channels, including Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn

### **BALAJI TELEFILMS LTD**

## **Content Development Intern**

08/2019 to 11/2019

I commenced my professional journey with an internship at Balaji Telefilms, one of the biggest movie production houses in India.

### Responsibilities

- I was entrusted with content development and the film's promotional activities for their upcoming movie 'Dreamgirl', a Bollywood blockbuster
- I was able to implement various campaigns before the launch, such as owning their social media platform

### PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS -

- I received a gold rank in The Duke of Edinburgh's International Award, which helped me learn new life skills and connect with the community
- I was selected by the committee at the International Soccer Programme for Girls in India, affiliated with FIFA, to represent my country in the Dana Cup, an international youth football tournament held in Hjørring, Denmark
- I represented my school in inter-school and state-level football matches and district-level athletics

- I pursued photography competitions and actively participated in debates at my school
- Participated in the Inter-School Model United Nations (WELMUN)
- I was a member of the Student Council at my college and helped organise many events and fests

### **EDUCATION** -

# BACHELOR'S IN MASS MEDIA : ADVERTISING

2021

- **H.R. College of Commerce and Economics**, Mumbai
  - I graduated with a CGPA of 8.20
  - Dissertation in Advertising

• Coursework in consumer behaviour

# DIPLOMA OF HIGHER EDUCATION Hopetown Girl's Schools , Dehradun, UT I got 85% in 12th grade. Additionally, secured a grade of 91.2% in class 10 Dissertation in Commerce CERTIFICATIONS Brand Management (Udemy) Digital Marketing (Udemy) LANGUAGES

C2

Proficient

English:

English, Hindi: First Language

Proficient

Hindi:

C2